Iruka...
What is it, Lord Hokage?
((ヒルゼン : イルカよ。
(イルカ)なんです？ 火影様。
I know how you feel.
(九喇嘛)グォ～ッ！
You grew up just like him...
without a parent's love.
(ヒルゼン)お前の気持も
わからんではないが→
あやつも
お前と同じ親の愛情を…。
Huh? Who could it be at this hour?
(イルカ)ん？ 誰だ こんな時間に？
Mizuki Sensei!
What's wrong?
Please come to
Lord Hokage's office!
ミズキ先生 どうしたんです？
It seems Naruto pulled a prank
and stole the Sacred Scroll!
(ミズキ)火影様のところへ。
どうやら ナルト君が イタズラで
封印の書を持ち出したらしくて。
What?!
It's been over half a day
since the scroll was taken.
ええっ！
Find Naruto immediately!
(ヒルゼン)書が盗まれて
半日以上経っておる。
急いでナルトを捜すのじゃ。
Naruto!
Hurry! Give me the scroll now!
ナルト 早く巻物を
こっちに渡すんだ。
Mizuki's after the scroll!
ミズキが巻物を狙ってる。
グハッ！
グッ。
Why... Naruto?
どうしてだ ナルト。
How did you know that
I wasn't Iruka?
どうして
イルカじゃないとわかった？
(ナルト)ヘヘッ。
I'm Iruka...
イルカは 俺だ。
He's a superior student
that I acknowledge.
あいつは この俺が認めた
優秀な生徒だ。
He perseveres and
he's earnest,
but he's clumsy
and no one accepts him.
努力家で一途で
そのくせ不器用で→
He knows what human suffering is.
誰からも認めてもらえなくて…。
あいつはもう
人の心の苦しみを知っている。
He is no longer
the monster fox.
He's Hidden Leaf's—!
今は もう バケ狐じゃない。
(あいつは 木ノ葉隠れの里の…))
That was a dream?
夢か…。
The                     Message
kara no kokoro wo terasu mono wa nani?
What brightens up an empty heart?
sakebi tsuzukeru hikari todoku made
I will keep on singing until the light reaches you
falling through the cracks kurayami e ochiteku
Falling through the cracks, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me the story of your life mada michi no tochuu
Tell me the story of your life, We're still on our way
anata o watashi wa zettai akiramenai
I will never give up on you
osaerarenai shoudou nanigenai hibi wa aijyou
Urges I can't suppress, I live for the ordinary days
natsukashii kaze ni furimukeba itsud
When I turn my cheek to a nostalgic wind
emo anata no koe ga suru yo
I always hear your voice
underdog wa wander around
Underdog will Wander around
mawari michi shitemo nigeru yori mashi yo
Even if I take the long way around,
it's better than running away
jibun de jibun o shinjirare nakucha dare wo shinjiru no?
If I can't learn to believe in myself,
then who can I believe in?
hikari ni sono te kazase
Hold up your hand to the light
shining through the clouds kurayami e ochiteku
Shining through the clouds, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me what is on your mind hateshinai yume wo
Tell me what is on your mind,
Chasing the never ending dream
oikake bokura wa zettai akiramenai
We will never give up
kotae no nai jinsei ni kujike sou ni naru kedo
Discouraged by a life without answers, but I...
don’t give it up! keep it up! turn it upside down!
Don't give it up! Keep it up! Turn it upside down!
kokoro wa tsunagatteru yo tatoe tooku hanaretemo
Our hearts will always be connected,
no matter how far apart we may be
tomo ni tomo ni ikiteyukou
Let's share this life together
"THE THIRD HOKAGE"
Iruka Sensei, what's this all about?
Remember, you recorded me before?
(木ノ葉丸)ええ～！
イルカ先生 どういうことだコレ？
だから 前に一度→
Huh? Oh yeah...
– That boring message with no style or punch?
– Naruto, Hinata...
撮影してもらったときの
あっただろ？
えっ？ ああ あのヒネリもオチもない
普通のメッセージの？
Congratulations on your marriage.
C'mon, don't say that.
Could you just use that one?
そういうこと言わずに➡
But you said you wanted
to re-do it,
とにかく
あのときの映像使ってくれよ。
so I've been waiting around
this whole time!
だって イルカ先生が
やり直したいって言うから→
I'm sorry about that.
But the more I think about it,
今までずっと待ってたんだぞコレ。
the less sure I am about
what to say to Naruto.
それは悪かったな。
でも考えれば考えるほど→
But you held out for so long,
今のナルトになんて言っていいのか
わからなくて…。
so you should just
make up your mind
けど ここまで粘ったんだから→
and send him a cool,
heartfelt message, okay?
You're the only one left!
ビシッと かっこよく
感動のメッセージを贈ってほしいぞ。
I'm sorry. I'll treat to you
a bowl of ramen next time,
あとは イルカ先生だけなんだぞコレ。
so please forgive me!
Okay?
すまなかったな。 今度
ラーメンおごるから許してくれ なっ。
Hey! Tsukune, Sansho, Mibuna!
You were messing around with
the Third Hokage's statue again, weren't you?!
おい ツクネ サンショ ミブナ！
ま～た三代目の像にイタズラしたな！
"NINJA ACADEMY"
I can't believe it's almost next week...
Naruto's wedding.
(サドル)ついに来週ですね。
ナルトさんの結婚式。
Will you be making
an official congratulatory speech?
イルカ先生
やっぱり祝辞とか言うんですか？
Oh no... I think Lord Hokage
will be taking care of that.
えっ いやいや
そういうことは全部→
火影様がやられるんじゃないかな。
Iruka Sensei!
Oh, you're Ichiraku's—!
(アヤメ)イルカ先生！
Is anything the matter?
You haven't been around
at all lately.
ああ 一楽の…。
Oh, I just wanted to hold off
until I figured out
どうしたんです？ 最近
来てくれないじゃないですか。
what to say for the message
that Konohamaru asked me to do.
いや あれは
木ノ葉丸に頼まれてた➡
I have to practice some self-restraint.
お祝いのメッセージを
思いつくまでのことだから。
So... Did you finish your message?
これからは 摂生しないとね。
Well... uh...
じゃあ お祝いのメッセージ
終わったんですね？
I'll stop by again soon.
ええ… まぁ。
Please say hello to your dad.
また そのうち
すぐ伺いますから→
親父さんにも
よろしく伝えてください。
What? That's easy!
Then can you jump to here?!
なんだ そんなの簡単じゃん。
じゃあ ここまで飛べっかよ！
たぁっ！
Oww!
I knew it.
Shut up!
I won't lose at fence-jumping though!
でっ！
あちゃ～。
やっぱりな。
It's all thanks to you.
うるせえ！
塀飛び越えなら負けねえ！
You acknowledged me back then.
((イルカ先生のおかげだ。
あのとき 先生
俺のことを認めてくれただろ。
That was the first time.
That's why,
I am who I am today.
初めてだったんだ。
だから今の俺があるんだ。
I was able to change.
Naruto expressed
his feelings so directly.
(俺は変われたんだ))
《ナルトは あんなに まっすぐに→
What am I doing?
思いを
伝えてくれたっていうのに➡
俺は なにをしてるんだ》
痛っ！ 熱っ！
Oh man...
わわっ…。
I really shouldn't do things
I'm not used to!
も～お 慣れないことは
やるもんじゃないな。
Huh?
Yes?
ん？ はい！
Naruto!
あ…。
H-Hey, Iruka Sensei...
ナルト！
W-What's wrong?
よう！ イルカ先生…。
Nothing. It's... well...
ど… どうしたんだ？
I was thinking about you.
いや～ その… なんつうんだ？
いや～ 久しぶりに
イルカ先生のこと 思い出してさ。
And I just stopped by
to see if you were alive!
What the hell's that about?
You know,
I'm gonna be getting married.
ちゃんと生きてっかな？ って。
なんだよ？ それ…。
And you're still single and all,
ほら！ 俺も結婚するわけだろ？
so I was worried about you
being alone.
I'm coming in!
独り者のイルカ先生が
やっぱ 心配なんだってばよ。
Hey, wait! I'm in the middle of...
ってことで
ちょっと おじゃまするぜ。
What happened?
あぁ～！ 待て!!
今 大変なことに…。
Uh, just some stuff.
何があったんだ？
But what about you?
What's going on?
いや ちょっと いろいろな…。
Uh... well...
とにかく 何か用があるんだろ？
なんだ？
Oh yeah! R-Ramen!
あぁ え… え～っと…。
Want to go get some ramen?
あっ！ そうだ!!
ラーメン… ラーメン食いにいかねえか？
Ramen?
Actually, I'm making dinner
right now.
ラーメン？
今 俺 飯作ってるところでな…。
Oh, that explains
this crime scene right here.
Y-Yeah...
You really should hurry up
and get married, Iruka Sensei!
それで この惨状なのか。
あ… あぁ…。
やっぱ イルカ先生も
早く結婚しねえと ダメだな。
Shut up!
What about you?
Are you sure you should
be neglecting Hinata right now?
うるさい！ お前こそ➡
"Neglecting"?
ヒナタをほったらかしにして
大丈夫なのか。
We're not married yet,
so don't worry about it.
ほったらかしって なんだよ？
Don't worry about it?
まだ 俺たち 結婚してないんだし
気にすんなって！
My single days are numbered!
気にするな？
I'm gonna have fun
with everything I've got—
残り少ない独身生活
思いっきり 羽目外すってばよ…。
You fool!
Do you even have a clue about
バカ野郎！
how hard Hinata is working,
preparing for your wedding?!
お前な… ヒナタが どんな思いで→
お前と結婚しようとしているのか
わかってるのか!?
What's wrong, Iruka Sensei?
It seems there were a lot of things
どうしたんだ？ イルカ先生…。
I failed to teach you
on how to be a human!
やはり 人として
教えきれてないことが→
I take full responsibility!
たくさん あったようだな。
Come with me!
すべて 俺の責任だ！
I'm gonna knock some sense
into you!
Huh?
来い！ 叩き直してやる!!
え… わっ！
Where are we going, Iruka Sensei?!
To Hinata's!
え… どこ行くんだよ？ イルカ先生！
I'm going to apologize to her
ヒナタのところだ！
for raising you into such
a thoughtless man.
こんな思いやりのない男に
育ててしまって➡
Please stop!
すまなかったと
謝りに行く！
If Hinata's around,
I won't be able to say
やめてくれよ！
what I wanted to talk to you about!
ヒナタと一緒じゃ 話したいことも
話せねえんだって。
What do you want to talk about?
T-That's why I thought
we could have some ramen,
何を話したいんだ？
and you could have
a drink or two...
だ… だから
ラーメンでも食いながらさ…。
ほら… 先生は ちょっとくらい→
and we could have
an enjoyable conversation and
酒なんかも
飲んじゃっていいんだぜ。
have some fun.
それで 賑やかに
話せばいいじゃんか。
Enough.
羽目外しちゃってさ！
もう いい。
I guess I didn't need to mull over
what to say and
how to congratulate you.
お前を どう祝ってやるべきか
何を伝えればいいのか→
いろいろ
考える必要はなかったな。
I have a request...
頼みがあるんだ。
A request?
頼み？
Will you attend the ceremony
as my father?
俺の父親として 結婚式に
出席してもらえねえかな？
Naruto...?
Is that what you wanted
to talk about?
ナルト…。
頼みって
そういうことだったのか。
You can leave it to me!
任せておけ。
Iruka Sensei!
イルカ先生…。
Thank you.
What are you talking about, Naruto?
ありがとう。
I should be saying that.
Thank you!
何言ってるんだ？ ナルト！
俺のほうこそ ありがとう。
Cut it out.
See you later, Iruka Sensei!
やめてくれよ。
じゃあな！ イルカ先生。
Yeah!
おう！
う… うぅ…。
"ICHIRAKU"
Good evening...
– Hey!
– Oh...
こんばんは。
– Welcome!
– What's going on?
(テウチ)おう！
あら！
Something troublin' you again?
いらっしゃい。
どうしたんですか？
Huh? No...
何か また悩みでもできたかい？
えっ？ いや…。
I was just thinking about how glad
I am I chose this profession.
そうじゃなくて 今の仕事を
選んでよかったと思ってて…。
I see.
So, what'll you have today?
Oh! A large miso char siu ramen topped
with naruto fishcake.
そうかい。
で… 今日は何にする？
あ… みそチャーシュー大盛り。
トッピングに ナルトつけてください。
One large miso char siu ramen!
Okay, one large-size miso
char siu ramen coming right up!
(テウチ)あいよ！
みそチャーシュー大盛り。
(アヤメ)は～い みそチャーシュー大盛りね。
Hinata!
Iruka Sensei?
(イルカ)ヒナタ！
How are the preparations going?
(ヒナタ)イルカ先生！
どうだ？ 準備は順調か？
Just about all done.
Now, we just have to wait
for the big day.
That's good.
(ヒナタ)はい。
あとは当日を待つだけです。
Anyway, I...
have something to tell you.
そうか。 そりゃ よかった。
It's about the wedding ceremony...
実はな 報告があって。
お前たちの結婚式だけど…。
You're going to attend
as Naruto's father, aren't you?
ナルト君の父親として
参列していただけるんですよね。
Oh, you knew?
Yeah, of course you would!
あ… やっぱ 聞いてたか。
そりゃ そうだよな。 アハハハハ！
Seems it was on Naruto's mind
for a long time.
ナルト君
ずっと考えてたみたいなんです。
You're definitely
Naruto's teacher, Iruka Sensei.
確かに ナルト君は
イルカ先生の教え子ですけど→
But he didn't want to consider
your relationship
simply as a "student-teacher"
or "mentor" relationship.
単純に 教え子と恩師の関係で
片づけていいのか って…。
Huh?!
But I kind of feel like
it shouldn't be coming
えっ？
from the point of view
of a teacher to his student.
((イルカ : それを ただ単純に→
(師と教え子の関係で
片づけてよいものか…))
Naruto was thinking
the same thing as I was.
《ナルトのヤツ…。
俺と同じことを…》
And so, his answer was to ask me
to attend as his father.
それで その答えが→
Yes.
親として出席する
ってことだったのか。
And so, please continue
to support him, Father!
はい そういうわけで
今後もよろしくお願いします。
お父さん。
Y-Yes...
It's sort of embarrassing
to be asked so formally.
お おう。
アハハ 改めて言われると
なんか照れるな。
So anyway...
ウフフ。
それでなんだが…。
What is this?
It's not much, but please put it
toward the reception fees.
なんですか これ？
What?!
少ないけど
披露宴の費用にあててくれ。
Naruto asked me to stand in
as his father.
ええ!?
I have to do this much, at least.
ナルトの父として
出席させてもらうなら→
Please don't worry about that!
これくらいのことは
しなくちゃな。
Please!
そんなこと
心配しないでください！
I-Is that so?
お願いします！
そうか？
I guess I'll just have to
accept your answer
じゃあ俺も おとなしく
結婚式当日を待つしかないな。
and wait for the big day.
I wish I could've done something
fatherly though...
少しくらい親らしいことを
してやりたかったが…。
W-What is it?
ウフフ。
なんだ？
You look just like my father,
with that expression.
ウフフ。 うちの父そっくりです
そういう姿。
You're already acting like
the father of the groom.
Y-You think so?
すでに
新郎の父って感じですね。
そ そうか？
アハハ…。
3...2...
(木ノ葉丸)３ ２ １ キューだぞ。
1...
Rolling!
"NINJA ACADEMY"
Naruto, Hinata...
Congratulations on your wedding!
ナルト ヒナタ 結婚おめでとう。
Naruto!
ナルト。
What's the matter, Iruka Sensei?
ハハ。
どうしたんだ イルカ先生？
Lost for words again?
Oh, sorry, sorry.
また思いつかなくなったのか？
This time, I'll do it right!
ああ すまん すまん。
So can I start over,
just one more time?
今度こそ大丈夫だから
もう１回だけやり直させてくれ。
はあ。
"A PERFECT DAY FOR A CELEBRATION"
Naruto, Hinata...
Congratulations on your wedding!
Please create a home
as bright as the morning sun!
(サクラ)ナルト ヒナタ！
(２人)結婚おめでとう！
May you always be happy!
(リー)この朝日のような
明るい家庭を築いてください！
Happy wedding!
Congratulations!
Do your best!
(テンテン)お幸せに。
(ガイ)ハッピ-ウエディング！
Don't gorge yourself on
delicious home-cooked meals!
(いの)おめでとう！
(シカマル)頑張れよ。
Congratulations.
Congratulations!
(チョウジ)おいしい手料理
食べすぎないでね。
"CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR WEDDING!"
Mr Naruto! Miss Hinata!
Congratulations!
(シノ)おめでとう。
(キバ)おめでとう！
(みんな)ナルトさん ヒナタさん
ご結婚おめでとうございます！
Congratulations on your wedding!
Stop by once in a while for
miso char siu ramen, okay?
ご結婚
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations, you two.
たまには
みそチャーシュー食べに来なよ。
Congratulations!
"CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR WEDDING!
LEAF'S UNOFFICIAL MASCOT CONGRATULATIONS"
Naruto, Miss Hinata...
A lot of things have happened,
(紅)２人とも おめでとう。
(ミライ)おめでとう！
but congratulations on your wedding.
(大蛇丸)ナルト君 ヒナタさん。
Big Brother Naruto, you did it!
いろいろあったけど
結婚おめでとう。
I'm gonna do my best too!
ナルト兄ちゃん ついにやったな！
俺も頑張るぜ！
Naruto Uzumaki,
congratulations on your wedding.
Dear Naruto, do your best.
(我愛羅)
うずまきナルト 結婚おめでとう。
Yeah!
(エー)ナルトよ 頑張るのだぞ。
(ビー)イエー！
Naruto, Hinata...
Congratulations on your wedding!
Help each other and may you
have long lasting happiness!
(カカシ)ナルト ヒナタ 結婚おめでとう。
お互い助け合って
末永くお幸せに。
Naruto! Hinata!
Congratulations on your wedding!
ナルト ヒナタ 結婚おめでとう。
Hinata, Naruto is absent-minded
and reckless
ヒナタ ドジでおっちょこちょいで
向こう見ずのナルトには→
and will need your support.
I ask you to
please take care of him!
お前の支えが必要だ。
ナルトのことを
どうかよろしく頼む。
Naruto, I just have this
to say to you...
ナルト お前には多くは言わん。
You better make Hinata happy!
絶対ヒナタを幸せにしろ。
Okay! That was perfect!
オッケー！ 最高だぞ コレ！
Phew...
It went without a hitch!
いや～ 無事終わった。
"UZUMAKI-HYUGA WEDDING RECEPTION"
Uh...
Could you get
the receiving desk set up?
Lord Kakashi!
ああ もう先に受付の準備を
終わらせちゃって。
Like I said, drop the "lord."
(シズネ)カカシ様。
The Lords Kage have arrived.
いや だから
様はやめてって 様は。
Huh? Already?!
影の皆様が ご到着です。
ええ？
Shall I escort them?
Yes. It's rude to keep them waiting.
もう来ちゃった？
お連れしましょうか？
ああ そうだね。
Huh?
Hey, Kazekage entourage!
We're the Lightning entourage...
Here to give our wedding blessings.
うん？ ヨー！
♪♪「風影一行 俺ら雷影一行
今日は祝言日和で絶好」
So forget the past...
Let's be friends 'til the last.
Of course!
I don't feel like fighting
like brats anymore.
♪♪「過去は忘れて仲良くいこう」
(カンクロウ)もちろんじゃん。
Oh say, see my gift
and be surprised
もう ガキみたく
張り合う気はねえよ。
Even the couple will rapturize.
♪♪「ところで 俺のお祝い見て驚け」
Enough already!
♪♪「あいつら ２人は おのろけ」
The reception desk is now open.
やめんか！
– Hey, where'd Temari go?
– Please sign in, in order of arrival.
(シズネ)では
披露宴の受付を開始します。
I haven't seen her since we came.
おい テマリは どこに行った？
"EBISU"
さっきから見ないな。
How much are you giving them,
Ebisu Sensei?
Well, it's accepted etiquette
for working adults like us
エビス先生は
どのくらい包んだんだ コレ？
to give about...
Huh?!
(エビス)まあ 社会人は
これくらいが常識かと。
It's okay to give that little?
I put five bills in my envelope.
え!? それくらいでいいのか？
俺 ５枚入れちゃったぞ コレ。
What?!
Did you say five?!
I'll lose face as a teacher.
えぇ!? ご… ５枚ですか！
You mean, our wedding gift?
《教師としての私のメンツが…》
We'll be giving...
"FREE NARUTO FISHCAKE TOPPING"
... this!
あ お祝いですか？
Not that one, Dad!
うちは やっぱり これですね。
Huh? Oh... this one.
違う お父さん！
あ？ おう こっちか。
Seriously?
Now listen, Lee!
When we honor people,
we hone our mind and spirit.
まったく もう。
いいか リーよ。
人を祝うことで己の心身を鍛える。
That's what a reception's for!
What you mean is, to
never forget to train, even at a party!
披露宴とは そういうものだ。
Naturally!
パーティーでも 修業のことは
忘れるなということですね。
Look, people are staring like
you're weird, so will you cut it out?
おう もちろんだ！
We'll start with dumbbell juggling!
Let's go!
もう みんな変な目で見てるから
やめなさいよ。
Yes, Guy Sensei!
では早速 ダンベルジャグリングいくぞ！
はい ガイ先生！
What a day! What a joyous day!
(２人)ハッ！
Yes! This training is especially joyous!
めでたい！ 実にめでたいぞ リー！
You two have too much joy
in your heads!
はい めでたい特訓です。
あんたたちの頭が めでたいわ！
So? Did you get a hold
of the honey wine?
Of course!
(紅)それで 蜂蜜酒は入手できた？
We're gonna tell Naruto about
the history of the Senju Clan.
(キバ)当然！ ナルトの野郎に→
You're that versed in history
to do that?
千手一族の歴史を
語り聞かせてやるんだ。
Huh?! Well, yeah...
そんな説明できるほど
歴史に詳しかったっけ？
Why don't you run it by me first?
え!? あぁ まあな。
Well, that's... uh.
ちょっと私に説明してみなさい。
いや それはその…。
Giddy up!
Run!
Mirai, what are you doing?
ハイヨー！ 走れ！
Playing horsey-back!
ミライ 何をやっている？
お馬さんごっこ。
Akamaru is a dog.
You can't ride a dog and
call it horsey-back riding.
赤丸は犬だ。
Then, doggie-back riding!
犬に乗って お馬さんごっこは
変だと思うぞ。
True, it is doggie-back riding.
But Akamaru looks a little tired.
じゃあ お犬さんごっこ。
たしかに お犬さんごっこだが
赤丸は少し疲れているようだ。
You might want to come down.
It's because...
No! I wanna ride some more!
かわいそうだから
下りてあげるのだ。
I guess I have no choice.
なぜなら…。
いや！ まだ乗ってたい！
Let's go Shino-back riding, then.
しかたない。 では…。
– Was Shino always that good with little kids?
– Higher! Higher!
おシノさんごっこで我慢しろ。
Seems he thinks he might
be suited to teaching.
シノって あんなに
子供あやすの上手かったっけ？
なんか 先生が向いてるかもとか
思ってるみたいっすよ。
What are you smiling about?
Who said I was smiling?
(テマリ)なにを ニヤけているんだ？
Whatever...
誰も ニヤけてなんかねえよ。
よく言うな。
Men go to wedding receptions
to meet the friends of the bride,
don't they?
こういう披露宴での
男の楽しみは→
That's not it.
新婦の友達と
知り合いになることだろ。
What a drag! Let's go over there.
んなわけねえだろ。
面倒くせえな あっち行くぞ。
Hey!
Oh, sweet!
うわっ！ ちょっ…。
It's definitely gonna be sweet.
お!? 甘い…
これは絶対 甘いよ。
When did they hook up?
あの２人 いつの間に
あんなんなってたんだろ。
Who are you talking about?
Shikamaru and Temari...
(サイ)誰の話？
シカマルとテマリ。
Did you know they were like that?
Hmm.
あんな感じになってるって
知ってた？
Anyway, everyone probably
thinks about us the same way.
うん。 それはともかく→
周りの人は 僕らにも
同じ感想を持つと思うよ。
"CONGRATULATIONS"
Sasuke...
サスケ君。
What's the matter, Iruka Sensei?
Is something still worrying you?
どうしたんです イルカ先生？
Well...
まだ何か心配ですか？
It's going to be all right.
Thanks to you, Iruka Sensei,
えぇ。
大丈夫。
we have guard duty covered
with enough shinobi.
イルカ先生の助言のおかげで
警備も当直の忍も万全です。
No, that was all you, Kakashi.
No, I didn't do anything.
いえいえ それは カカシさんが。
I just helped a little.
いや 俺は何もしてませんよ。
It's all thanks to the bonds
Naruto forged.
ほんの少し手伝っただけです。
すべては
ナルトの作り上げた絆のおかげです。
Naruto's here, and
that's why everyone is here today.
ナルトがいたから
俺たちが みんなが ここにいる。
I'm sure he will make Hinata happy.
あいつは
必ず ヒナタを幸せにしますよ。
Are you still worried?
Well...
それでも何か心配ですか？
えぇ。
I forgot to prepare
my final message.
最後の挨拶
考えてくるの忘れました。
え？ ハハハハ。
Brother Neji...
I'm going to get married.
《ネジ兄さん… 私 結婚します》
Elder Sister! It's time!
All right!
(ハナビ)姉様 時間だよ！
Wow!
You look so beautiful, Elder Sister!
はい。
Doesn't she, Father?
(ハナビ)うわぁ！
姉様 すごいきれい。
ねぇ 父様。
Okay, ready to go?
よし 行くか。
"CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR WEDDING!"
kakaeta omou i tokitoshite
Sometimes, the feelings we have
kazoe kirenai itami o
Cause us immense pain
yuzurenai hokori mune ni
We've lived this entire time
imamade ikite kitadarou
With unshakeable pride in our hearts
tatakau koto de mamotte
Defending by fighting
omoigakenaku nakushite
With unexpected losses
kizutsukiai ma nande
We learn as we hurt one another
taisetsu na koto ni kizukudarou
Will we realize what's most important?
koe ga todokanai
My voice cannot reach you
soredemo (soredemo)
Even so
kokoro shinjite iyou
Let's trust our hearts
zenshin zenrei kimi wo mamoru yo
I will protect you with every essence of my being
towa ni sou towa ni
For all eternity
nankaidatte tachiagare yo
Stand up again and again
sono ishi de (sono ishi de)
By your own volition
ungai souten asu wo egaku yo
Don't give in; create a new day
tomo ni sou tomo ni
Together with friends
itsudatte akirameru
Never ever give up
na michi wo hirakou
Let's open up the path
ruru
On and on
"THANK YOU FOR ALL OF YOUR SUPPORT!"